Guide to the James Hazen Hyde Collection of Allegorical Prints of the Four Continents ca. 1500-ca.1900 PR 27
New-York Historical Society
- Series XII: Religious, French
  - Agnus Dei Qui Tollis Peccata Mundi (JHH# 5962 / Enregistre# 1585) (Folder Portfolio 9)
    Artist: Printmaker: Ios, Ioa. and Catharina Klauber Publisher: Ios. Ioa. and Catharina Klauber
  - Ecce en im ex Hoc Beatam (JHH# 5965 / Enregistre# 1586) (Folder Portfolio 9)
    17th Century Swiss Etching
    Artist: Johann Christoff Storer Printmaker: Bartholome Kilin Publisher:
  - S. Vincentius Fererius Ord (JHH# 5978 / Enregistre# 1587) (Folder Portfolio 9)
  - Wer will seelig werden (JHH# 5979 / Enregistre# 1588) (Folder Portfolio 9)
    Artist: I.A. Stockmann Printmaker: Publisher: Catharina Klauber
  - Accendetur Velut Ignis (JHH# 6263 / Enregistre# 1589) (Folder Portfolio 9)
    17th Century Spanish Etching
    Artist: Petrus Costo Printmaker: Petrus Costo Publisher:
  - S. Ignacio de Loyala (JHH# 6713 / Enregistre# 1590) (Folder Portfolio 9)
- Series XIII: Images D'Epinal, French
  - Amerika (JHH# 302 / Enregistre# 1591) (Folder Portfolio 10)
    19th Century German Lithograph, hand coloring
    Artist: Printmaker: Publisher: Fr. Wenizel
  - L'Europe (JHH# 940 / Enregistre# 1592) (Folder Portfolio 10)
    Artist: Dembour and Gangel Printmaker: Publisher:
  - L'Asie (JHH# 941 / Enregistre# 1593) (Folder Portfolio 10)
  - L'Asie (JHH# 943 / Enregistre# 1594) (Folder Portfolio 10)
  - L'Amerique (JHH# 944 / Enregistre# 1595) (Folder Portfolio 10)
  - Les Cinq Parties du Monde (JHH# 3130 / Enregistre# 1596) (Folder Portfolio 10)
    Artist: Printmaker: Publisher: Pellerin & Cie.
  - La Decouverte de L'Amerique Par Christophe Colomb. (JHH# 3132 / Enregistre# 1597) (Folder Portfolio 10)
    Artist: P.V.[?] Printmaker: Publisher: Pellerin and Cie.
  - La Decouverte de L'Amerique Par Christophe Colomb (JHH# 3133 / Enregistre# 1598) (Folder Portfolio 10)
    Artist: Printmaker: Publisher: Pinot and Sagaire
  - La Decouverte de L'Amerique Par Christophe Colomb (JHH# 3134 / Enregistre# 1599) (Folder Portfolio 10)
  - La Decouverte de L'Amerique Par Christophe Colomb (JHH# 3135 / Enregistre# 1600) (Folder Portfolio 10)
  - Loterie Alphabetique des Nations/ Petite Loterie (JHH# 3136 / Enregistre# 1601) (Folder Portfolio 10)
  - Loterie Alphabetique des 100 Images/Petite Jeu (JHH# 3137 / Enregistre# 1602) (Folder Portfolio 10)
  - Loterie Geographique des Divers Pays du Globe (JHH# 3138 / Enregistre# 1603) (Folder Portfolio 10)
  - Petite Loterie/ Loterie du Polichinel (JHH# 3139 / Enregistre# 1604) (Folder Portfolio 10)
  - Construction Petit Format (JHH# 3140 / Enregistre# 1605) (Folder Portfolio 10)
    Artist: P. Didion Printmaker: Publisher: Delhalt
  - Moeurs et Peuples Divers (JHH# 3141 / Enregistre# 1606) (Folder Portfolio 10)
    Artist: Printmaker: Publisher: Pellerin
  - Loterie de L'exposition Universelle de 1867 (2) (JHH# 3142 / Enregistre# 1607) (Folder Portfolio 10)
  - Les Quatre Parties du Monde/ Moeurs et Costumes (JHH# 3143 / Enregistre# 1608) (Folder Portfolio 10)
    Artist: Printmaker: Publisher: Gangel et P. Didion/ Pellerin
  - Loterie du Gros Lot/ L'Exposition (JHH# 3144 / Enregistre# 1609) (Folder Portfolio 10)
    Artist: Printmaker: Publisher: Gangel et P. Didion/ Pinot & Sagaire
  - [Playing Cards with the Four Continents] (JHH# 3146 / Enregistre# 1610), 1825 (Folder Portfolio 10)
    Artist: Printmaker: Publisher: Garnier-Allabre
  - Grands Exercices sur la Corde Tendue/ Danceurs (JHH# 3147 / Enregistre# 1611) (Folder Portfolio 10)
    Artist: Printmaker: Publisher: Blocquel/ Pellerin
  - / Habitant Distingue de L'Ile de Noukahiwa (JHH# 3148 / Enregistre# 1612), 1825 (Folder Portfolio 10)
  - Pantins. Danseurs Indiens et Espagnols (JHH# 3149 / Enregistre# 1613) (Folder Portfolio 10)
  - Sauvages de L'Amerique (JHH# 3150 / Enregistre# 1614) (Folder Portfolio 10)
  - Jue du Petit Voyageur (JHH# 3155 / Enregistre# 1615) (Folder Portfolio 10)
  - L'Europe (JHH# 7747 / Enregistre# 1616) (Folder Portfolio 10)
    Artist: Printmaker: Laujol Publisher: Agustoni Donato et Cie.
  - L'Asie (JHH# 7748 / Enregistre# 1617) (Folder Portfolio 10)
  - L'Afrique (JHH# 7749 / Enregistre# 1618) (Folder Portfolio 10)
- Series XIV: Frontispieces with Allegorical and Playing Cards
  - Nuovo Atlante Geogrfico Universale Tom III (JHH# 899 / Enregistre# 1619), 1801 (Folder Portfolio 11-1)
    19th Century Italian Etching
    Artist: Demetrio Dragon Printmaker: Demetrio Dragon Publisher: Pressola Calcografia
  - Nuovo Atlante Geogrfico Universale Tom II (JHH# 900 / Enregistre# 1620), 1797 (Folder Portfolio 11-1)
  - Nuovo Atlante Geogrfico Universale Tom I (JHH# 901 / Enregistre# 1621), 1792 (Folder Portfolio 11-1)
  - Mappamondo nell' uno e nell' Altro (JHH# 902 / Enregistre# 1622), 1801 (Folder Portfolio 11-1)
    Artist: Guglielmo Sanson Printmaker: Gio. Ma. Cassini Publisher:
  - Afrique (JHH# 1124 / Enregistre# 1623) (Folder Portfolio 11-1)
    Artist: Raimond Bonheur Printmaker: Laguillermie Publisher: Pelissier
  - Colonies Francaises (JHH# 1124 / Enregistre# 1623bis) (Folder Portfolio 11-1)
    Artist: Raimond Bonheur Printmaker: Laguillermie Publisher:
  - Le Theatre du Monde (JHH# 1480 / Enregistre# 1624), 1593 (Folder Portfolio 11-1)
    16th Century Dutch Etching, hand coloring
    Artist: Guillaume et Jean Blaeu Printmaker: Guillaume et Jean Blaeu Publisher:
  - Theatrum Orbis Terrarum (JHH# 1481 / Enregistre# 1625), 1595? (Folder Portfolio 11-1)
  - Canadian Pacific Distinctive Cruises (JHH# 1749 / Enregistre# 1626), 1927 (Folder Portfolio 11-1)
    20th Century English Reproductive print(s)
    Artist: Edmund Dulac Printmaker: Publisher:
  - Geographia Blauiana (JHH# 2054 / Enregistre# 1627) (Folder Portfolio 11-1)
    Artist: Printmaker: Ioan. Blaeu Publisher:
  - [Globe with Allegorical Figures of the Four Continents] (JHH# 3249 / Enregistre# 1628) (Folder Portfolio 11-1)
    19th Century English Etching, engraving
  - Nosce Te Ipsum (JHH# 3713 / Enregistre# 1630) (Folder Portfolio 11-1)
    18th? Century Dutch? Etching, hand coloring
    Artist: Salomon Printmaker: Publisher:
  - Afrique (JHH# 3805 / Enregistre# 1631) (Folder Portfolio 11-1)
  - Europe Ancienne (JHH# 3806 / Enregistre# 1632) (Folder Portfolio 11-1)
  - Mappe-Mondes (JHH# 3807 / Enregistre# 1633) (Folder Portfolio 11-1)
  - Atlas Universel (JHH# 3824 / Enregistre# 1634), 1757 (Folder Portfolio 11-1)
    Artist: Printmaker: Jean Charles Baquoy Publisher: Boudet
  - Carte du Theatre de la Guerre (JHH# 3947 / Enregistre# 1635), 1778 (Folder Portfolio 11-1)
    Artist: Printmaker: Publisher: Esnauts et Rapilly
  - Atlas Nouveau (JHH# 4095 / Enregistre# 1636) (Folder Portfolio 11-1)
    17th Century Dutch Etching
    Artist: Romeyn de Hooghe Printmaker: Publisher: Jean Covens and Corneille Mortier
  - L'Amerique Meridionale (JHH# 4096 / Enregistre# 1637), 1700 (Folder Portfolio 11-1)
    Artist: G. de L'Isle Printmaker: G. de L'Isle Publisher: G. de L'Isle
  - Il Mappamondo (JHH# 4157 / Enregistre# 1638), 1774 (Folder Portfolio 11-2)
    Artist: Pietro Novelli Printmaker: Giulian Zuliani Publisher: Antonio Zatta
  - Die Port Sdetzung des alten und Neuen Europae (JHH# 4163 / Enregistre# 1639) (Folder Portfolio 11-2)
  - Europe Afrique Asie Ameriques (JHH# 4546 / Enregistre# 1640) (Folder Portfolio 11-2)
  - Urbium Praecipuarum Mundi Theatrum (JHH# 4677 / Enregistre# 1641) (Folder Portfolio 11-2)
    17th Century Dutch Etching, engraving, hand coloring
  - Atlas Francois (JHH# 4678 / Enregistre# 1642), 1695 (Folder Portfolio 11-2)
    Artist: Jean Dieu Printmaker: Publisher: St. Iaillot
  - L'Univers Illustre (JHH# 4691 / Enregistre# 1643) (Folder Portfolio 11-2)
    Artist: Louis Janet Printmaker: Publisher: A. Godard
  - The Earth (JHH# 4735 / Enregistre# 1644) (Folder Portfolio 11-2)
    17-18th Century English Etching, engraving
  - Thesurus Exoticorum (JHH# 4794 / Enregistre# 1645) (Folder Portfolio 11-2)
    17th Century German Etching, engraving
    Artist: Ronot Printmaker: Publisher: P. van den Berg
  - Theatre de L'Univers (JHH# 4795 / Enregistre# 1646), 1598 (Folder Portfolio 11-2)
    16th Century French Engraving
    Artist: Abraham Ortelius Printmaker: Publisher:
  - Frontispiece to Kelly's System of Geography (JHH# 4987 / Enregistre# 1647), 1817 (Folder Portfolio 11-2)
    19th Century English Engraving, stipple
  - Le Petit Atlas Maritime (JHH# 4990 / Enregistre# 1648), 1764 (Folder Portfolio 11-2)
    Artist: Arrivet Printmaker: Arrivet Publisher:
  - Les Estats Empires Royaumes et Prin (JHH# 4991 / Enregistre# 1649), 1628 (Folder Portfolio 11-2)
  - Les Estats Empires et Principautez du Monde (JHH# 5031 / Enregistre# 1650), 1615 (Folder Portfolio 11-2)
  - Cosmographie in foure Books (JHH# 5032 / Enregistre# 1651), 1669 (Folder Portfolio 11-2)
    17th Century English Engraving
    Artist: Printmaker: Io. Filliani Publisher: Anne Seile
  - Planisphere (JHH# 5035 / Enregistre# 1652) (Folder Portfolio 11-2)
    19th Century French Engraving, hand coloring
    Artist: Printmaker: Publisher: Lemercier
  - Europe (JHH# 5036 / Enregistre# 1653) (Folder Portfolio 11-2)
    Artist: Raimond Bonheur Printmaker: Laguillermie Publisher: A. Combette
  - Asie (JHH# 5037 / Enregistre# 1654) (Folder Portfolio 11-2)
  - Amerique Meridionale (JHH# 5038 / Enregistre# 1655) (Folder Portfolio 11-2)
  - Amerique Septentrionale (JHH# 5039 / Enregistre# 1656) (Folder Portfolio 11-2)
  - Oceanie (JHH# 5040 / Enregistre# 1657) (Folder Portfolio 11-2)
  - Suite de Vues de Cotes Maritimes (JHH# 5044 / Enregistre# 1658) (Folder Portfolio 11-3)
    19th Century France Etching, engraving
    Artist: Printmaker: Y. Le Gouaz Publisher: Y. Le Gouaz
  - Amstelodami ex Officina (JHH# 5454 / Enregistre# 1660), 1685 (Folder Portfolio 11-3)
    Artist: J. Harrewijn Printmaker: J. Harrewijn Publisher:
  - Atlas Contractus (JHH# 5455 / Enregistre# 1661) (Folder Portfolio 11-3)
    Artist: J. Webbers Printmaker: J. Visscher Publisher: Visscher
  - Mercurio Geografico (JHH# 5552 / Enregistre# 1662) (Folder Portfolio 11-3)
    17th Century Italian Etching, engraving
    Artist: Francesco Galli? Printmaker: Publisher: Gio. Giacomo de Rossi
  - Der Prophet Daniel (JHH# 5644 / Enregistre# 1663) (Folder Portfolio 11-3)
    16th? Century German woodcut
  - Mappe Monde (JHH# 5959 / Enregistre# 1664) (Folder Portfolio 11-3)
    18th Century Dutch Etching
    Artist: Printmaker: Pierre vander Aa Publisher: Pierre vander Aa
  - Amerique Oceanie Asie Afrique (JHH# 6114 / Enregistre# 1665) (Folder Portfolio 11-3)
    Artist: Fauchery Printmaker: Fauchery Publisher:
  - L'Amerique selon les nouvelles observations (JHH# 6151 / Enregistre# 1666) (Folder Portfolio 11-3)
    18th Century Dutch Etching, engraving
    Artist: J. Goeree Printmaker: J. Baptist Publisher: Pierre vander Aa
  - Europa Asia Africa (JHH# 6266 / Enregistre# 1667) (Folder Portfolio 11-3)
    15th [?] Century Italian [?] Woodcut
  - Le Theatre du Monde (JHH# 6421 / Enregistre# 1668), 1700 (Folder Portfolio 11-3)
    Artist: I. B. Nolin Printmaker: Publisher: I.B. Nolin
  - Toonneel des Aerdrycx (JHH# 6422 / Enregistre# 1669) (Folder Portfolio 11-3)
    16th Century Dutch Engraving
    Artist: Johan Blaeu Printmaker: Publisher: Johan Blaeu
  - Atlas Novus (JHH# 6423 / Enregistre# 1670) (Folder Portfolio 11-3)
    18th Century German Etching, engraving, hand coloring
    Artist: Jacob Christoph Weyerman Printmaker: Martin Gottfrid Publisher: Matthaeo Seutter
  - ` (JHH# 6424 / Enregistre# 1671) (Folder Portfolio 11-3)
  - [Allegory] (JHH# 6425 / Enregistre# 1672), 1712 (Folder Portfolio 11-3)
    18th Century Dutch Engraving, hand coloring
    Artist: Printmaker: Publisher: Ioannes van Keulen
  - Atlas sive Cosmographicae Meditationes (JHH# 7750 / Enregistre# 1673), 1607 (Folder Portfolio 11-3)
    Artist: Justus Hondius Printmaker: Cornelij Nicolaie Publisher: Petrus Montani
- Series XV: Allegorical, German
  - Europa Asia America Africa (JHH# 113 / Enregistre# 1674) (Folder Portfolio 12-1A)
  - Europa (JHH# 10002 / Enregistre# 1675), 1577 (Folder Portfolio 12-1A)
    16th Century German Etching
    Artist: Jost Amman [?] Printmaker: Publisher:
  - America (JHH# 331 / Enregistre# 1676) (Folder Portfolio 12-1A)
    18th Century German Mezzotint, etching
    Artist: Printmaker: Publisher: Georg Christoph Kilian
  - Europa (JHH# 522 / Enregistre# 1677) (Folder Portfolio 12-1A)
    Artist: I. Waxmuth Printmaker: I. Waxmuth Publisher: Ioan. Michael Motz
  - Asia (JHH# 523 / Enregistre# 1678) (Folder Portfolio 12-1A)
  - Africa (JHH# 524 / Enregistre# 1679) (Folder Portfolio 12-1A)
  - America (JHH# 525 / Enregistre# 1680) (Folder Portfolio 12-1A)
  - [Europe] (JHH# 2967 / Enregistre# 1681) (Folder Portfolio 12-1A)
    19th Century German Chromolithograph
    Artist: W.F. Printmaker: Publisher:
  - [Asia] (JHH# 2968 / Enregistre# 1682) (Folder Portfolio 12-1A)
  - [Africa] (JHH# 2969 / Enregistre# 1683) (Folder Portfolio 12-1A)
  - [America] (JHH# 2970 / Enregistre# 1684) (Folder Portfolio 12-1A)
  - America (JHH# 3279 / Enregistre# 1685) (Folder Portfolio 12-1A)
    Artist: J. Wachsmuth Printmaker: Johann Gottfried Seutter Publisher: Martin Engelbrecht
  - [Playing Cards] (JHH# 5223 / Enregistre# 1686) (Folder Portfolio 12-1A)
    19th Century German Etching
  - [Playing Cards] (JHH# 5274 / Enregistre# 1687) (Folder Portfolio 12-1A)
  - [Playing Cards] (JHH# 5275 / Enregistre# 1688) (Folder Portfolio 12-1A)
  - [Playing Cards] (JHH# 5276 / Enregistre# 1689) (Folder Portfolio 12-1A)
  - America (JHH# 5276 / Enregistre# 1690) (Folder Portfolio 12-1A)
    19th Century German Etching, hand coloring
    Artist: Printmaker: Publisher: Fr. Campo
  - Europa Asia Africa America (JHH# 5615 / Enregistre# 1691) (Folder Portfolio 12-1A)
    Artist: Printmaker: Publisher: Martin Engelbrecht
  - Europa (JHH# 5626 / Enregistre# 1692) (Folder Portfolio 12-1A)
    Artist: I. Wachsmuth Printmaker: Publisher: Martin Engelbrecht
  - Asia (JHH# 5627 / Enregistre# 1693) (Folder Portfolio 12-1A)
  - Africa (JHH# 5628 / Enregistre# 1694) (Folder Portfolio 12-1A)
  - America (JHH# 5629 / Enregistre# 1695) (Folder Portfolio 12-1A)
  - Europa (JHH# 5630 / Enregistre# 1696) (Folder Portfolio 12-1A)
    18th Century German Stipple
    Artist: G. B. Goz Printmaker: Publisher: M. Aulae
  - Asia (JHH# 5631 / Enregistre# 1697) (Folder Portfolio 12-1A)
  - Africa (JHH# 5632 / Enregistre# 1698) (Folder Portfolio 12-1A)
  - America (JHH# 5633 / Enregistre# 1699) (Folder Portfolio 12-1A)
  - Thesauri Philo-Polici (JHH# 5639 / Enregistre# 1700) (Folder Portfolio 12-1B)
    Artist: Eberhardt Kieferi [?] Printmaker: Publisher:
  - Europa (JHH# 5681 / Enregistre# 1701) (Folder Portfolio 12-1B)
    18th Century German Drypoint, engraving
  - Asia (JHH# 5682 / Enregistre# 1702) (Folder Portfolio 12-1B)
  - Africa (JHH# 5683 / Enregistre# 1703) (Folder Portfolio 12-1B)
  - America (JHH# 5684 / Enregistre# 1704) (Folder Portfolio 12-1B)
  - Europe Asia Africa America Etc. (JHH# 5806 / Enregistre# 1705) (Folder Portfolio 12-1B)
    Artist: J. Ch. Weigel Printmaker: Publisher:
  - Europe (JHH# 6280 / Enregistre# 1706) (Folder Portfolio 12-1B)
    Artist: Schülter Printmaker: B. Rode Publisher:
  - Asia (JHH# 6281 / Enregistre# 1707) (Folder Portfolio 12-1B)
    Artist: Schluter Printmaker: B. Rode Publisher:
  - Africa (JHH# 6282 / Enregistre# 1708) (Folder Portfolio 12-1B)
  - America (JHH# 6283 / Enregistre# 1709) (Folder Portfolio 12-1B)
  - Europa (JHH# 6527 / Enregistre# 1710) (Folder Portfolio 12-1B)
    Artist: Johann Daniel Preisler Printmaker: Johann Christoph Weigel Publisher:
  - [Asia] (JHH# 6528 / Enregistre# 1711) (Folder Portfolio 12-1B)
  - [America] (JHH# 6529 / Enregistre# 1712) (Folder Portfolio 12-1B)
  - [Africa] (JHH# 6530 / Enregistre# 1713) (Folder Portfolio 12-1B)
  - Maria Theresia (JHH# 6921 / Enregistre# 1714) (Folder Portfolio 12-1B)
    Artist: Printmaker: I.A. Steisslinger, Jünger Publisher: I.A. Steislinger, Jünger
  - Europa (JHH# 7380 / Enregistre# 1715) (Folder Portfolio 12-1B)
    Artist: Printmaker: Publisher: Johann Christian Leopold
  - Asia (JHH# 7381 / Enregistre# 1716) (Folder Portfolio 12-1B)
  - Africa (JHH# 7382 / Enregistre# 1717) (Folder Portfolio 12-1B)
  - America (JHH# 7383 / Enregistre# 1718) (Folder Portfolio 12-1B)
  - Europa (JHH# 7405 / Enregistre# 1719) (Folder Portfolio 12-1B)
    Artist: I. Wachsmuth Printmaker: J. Gottfried Publisher: Martin Engelbrecht
  - Asia (JHH# 7406 / Enregistre# 1720) (Folder Portfolio 12-1B)
  - Africa (JHH# 7407 / Enregistre# 1721) (Folder Portfolio 12-1B)
  - America (JHH# 7408 / Enregistre# 1722) (Folder Portfolio 12-1B)
  - Europa (JHH# 7588 / Enregistre# 1723) (Folder Portfolio 12-1B)
    Artist: Printmaker: Publisher: Ed. Gust.
  - Asia (JHH# 7589 / Enregistre# 1724) (Folder Portfolio 12-1B)
  - Amerika (JHH# 7590 / Enregistre# 1725) (Folder Portfolio 12-1B)
  - Ost und West Indisches und Tinesisches(?) (JHH# 110 / Enregistre# 1726) (Folder Portfolio 12-2)
  - Europa (JHH# 425 / Enregistre# 1727) (Folder Portfolio 12-2)
    Artist: G.S. Rosch Printmaker: Publisher: Ioh. Georg Hertel
  - Asia (JHH# 426 / Enregistre# 1728) (Folder Portfolio 12-2)
  - Africa (JHH# 427 / Enregistre# 1729) (Folder Portfolio 12-2)
  - America (JHH# 428 / Enregistre# 1730) (Folder Portfolio 12-2)
  - Emmanuel Regius Princeps Portugal (JHH# 1083 / Enregistre# 1731) (Folder Portfolio 12-2)
    Artist: Printmaker: Jacob Andreas Fridrich Publisher:
  - Mohitana (JHH# 1135 / Enregistre# 1732), 1834 (Folder Portfolio 12-2)
    19th Century German Reproductive print
    Artist: Printmaker: Publisher: Rheinhodt-Haus
  - L'Afrique L'Amerique (JHH# 2102 / Enregistre# 1733) (Folder Portfolio 12-2)
    Artist: C.P. Maj. Printmaker: Martin Engelbrecht Publisher: Martin Engelbrecht
  - Europe (JHH# 5622 / Enregistre# 1734) (Folder Portfolio 12-2)
    Artist: Jean Baptiste Enzensberger Printmaker: Jean Baptiste Enzensberger Publisher: Roselin
  - Asie (JHH# 5623 / Enregistre# 1735) (Folder Portfolio 12-2)
  - Afrique (JHH# 5624 / Enregistre# 1736) (Folder Portfolio 12-2)
  - Amerique (JHH# 5625 / Enregistre# 1737) (Folder Portfolio 12-2)
  - Europa (JHH# 5642 / Enregistre# 1738) (Folder Portfolio 12-2)
    Artist: Johann Franz Hueber Printmaker: Johann Georg Hertel Publisher: Johann Georg Hertel
  - Asia (JHH# 5643 / Enregistre# 1739) (Folder Portfolio 12-2)
  - L'Afrique (JHH# 6453 / Enregistre# 1740) (Folder Portfolio 12-2)
  - Athabaliba (JHH# 6525 / Enregistre# 1741) (Folder Portfolio 12-2)
  - Asia (JHH# 6535 / Enregistre# 1742) (Folder Portfolio 12-2)
  - America (JHH# 6536 / Enregistre# 1743) (Folder Portfolio 12-2)
  - Leopoldus I (JHH# 7247 / Enregistre# 1744) (Folder Portfolio 12-2)
    Artist: Printmaker: P. Kilian Publisher:
- Series XVI: Historical, American and French
  - Du Sein de la tyrannie naquit l'Independence (JHH# 111 / Enregistre# 1745), 1783? (Folder Portfolio 13-1)
    18-19th Century French Etching
  - Hommage Universel (JHH# 112 / Enregistre# 1746), 1791 (Folder Portfolio 13-1)
  - L'Angleterre Suppliante (JHH# 305 / Enregistre# 1747) (Folder Portfolio 13-1)
  - L'Angleterre Expirante (JHH# 306 / Enregistre# 1748) (Folder Portfolio 13-1)
  - [British babies fire on Native American babies] (JHH# 318 / Enregistre# 1749), 1784 (Folder Portfolio 13-1)
    18th Century French Softground etching and aquatint
    Artist: Curré Printmaker: Publisher:
  - Charles-Henri (JHH# 324 / Enregistre# 1750), 1729 (Folder Portfolio 13-1)
  - L'Independante (JHH# 340 / Enregistre# 1751) (Folder Portfolio 13-1)
    Artist: Printmaker: Publisher: Portier
  - Lafayette (JHH# 2101 / Enregistre# 1752) (Folder Portfolio 13-1)
  - In Memoriam (JHH# 2889 / Enregistre# 1754) (Folder Portfolio 13-1)
    19th Century French Reproductive print on copper
    Artist: E.D. Grafton Printmaker: Publisher: Fuchfarber and Moellmann
  - (JHH# 4030 / Enregistre# 1755), 1718 (Folder Portfolio 13-1)
    Artist: De Troy Printmaker: Cx Publisher:
  - The Royal Mail Line to New York (JHH# 4222 / Enregistre# 1756) (Folder Portfolio 13-1)
    20th Century English Color Lithograph
    Artist: Printmaker: Publisher: Sanders Phillips and Co.
- Series XVII: Political
  - L'Amerique Independante (JHH# 133 / Enregistre# 1757), 1778 (Folder Portfolio 13-2)
    Artist: A. Borel Printmaker: J.C. le Vasseur Publisher:
  - Eripuit Coelo Fulman Sceptrunque Tyrannis (JHH# 313 / Enregistre# 1758) (Folder Portfolio 13-2)
    18th Century French Etching and aquatint
    Artist: A. Borel Printmaker: A. Borel Publisher:
  - Le Couronnement de Franklin (JHH# 325 / Enregistre# 1759) (Folder Portfolio 13-2)
    Artist: Jean Honore Fragonard Printmaker: Publisher:
  - The Birth of American Liberty (JHH# 336 / Enregistre# 1760), 1784 (Folder Portfolio 13-2)
    18th Century English Soft ground etching
    Artist: S. Harding Printmaker: Ogborn Publisher: T. Macklin
  - Triumph of Liberty (JHH# 2772 / Enregistre# 1762), 1795-96 (Folder Portfolio 13-2)
    18th Century American Engraving
    Artist: J. F. Renault Printmaker: P.C. Verger Publisher:
  - [French-American Treaty] (JHH# 3735 / Enregistre# 1763) (Folder Portfolio 13-2)
    19th Century English Lithograph
    Artist: P. Adam Printmaker: C. Mott Publisher:
- Series XVIII: Franklin
  - Bold Jack! Pray, … (JHH# 311 / Enregistre# 1765) (Folder Portfolio 13-2)
  - Le Tombeau de Voltaire (JHH# 348 / Enregistre# 1766) (Folder Portfolio 13-2)
    Artist: L. V. Printmaker: C. M. Publisher: Alibert Md. D'Estampes
  - La Paix entre L'Angleterre, la France, Lespagne .. (JHH# 1099 / Enregistre# 1767), 1783 (Folder Portfolio 13-2)
    18th Century French Etching, drypoint
  - Le Docteur Francklin Couronne par la Liberte (JHH# 3152 / Enregistre# 1768) (Folder Portfolio 13-2)
    18th Century French Etching, aquatint
  - L'Apotre de la Liberte Immortalise (JHH# 3650 / Enregistre# 1770) (Folder Portfolio 13-2)
    Artist: Barincou Monbrun Printmaker: Barincou Monbrun Publisher:
  - Benjamin Franklin (JHH# 3780 / Enregistre# 1771), 1780 (Folder Portfolio 13-2)
    Artist: N.L.G.D.L.C.A.D.L. Printmaker: Publisher: Bligny
  - Etude graphique de la Terre (JHH# 3825 / Enregistre# 1772), 1870? (Folder Portfolio 13-2)
    Artist: V. Adam Printmaker: Langlume Publisher: Augustin Legrand
- Series XIX: Allegorical, French
  - Amerique (JHH# 327 / Enregistre# 1776) (Folder Portfolio 14-1A)
    Artist: H. Grevedon Printmaker: Lemercier Publisher: Aumont
  - L'Amerique (JHH# 332 / Enregistre# 1777) (Folder Portfolio 14-1A)
    19th Century French Soft ground etching
    Artist: Lemire aine Printmaker: Bertrand Publisher: Jean
  - L'Amerique (JHH# 335 / Enregistre# 1778) (Folder Portfolio 14-1A)
    Artist: Printmaker: Publisher: Noel Freres
  - L'Amerique (JHH# 344 / Enregistre# 1779) (Folder Portfolio 14-1A)
    Artist: Le Barbier l'aine Printmaker: Ruotte Publisher: Basses
  - L'Europe (JHH# 728 / Enregistre# 1780) (Folder Portfolio 14-1A)
    19th Century French Etching, aquatint
    Artist: Schopin Printmaker: A. Jazet Publisher: Goupile, Vibert & Cie
  - L'Asie (JHH# 730 / Enregistre# 1781) (Folder Portfolio 14-1A)
  - L'Afrique (JHH# 731 / Enregistre# 1782) (Folder Portfolio 14-1A)
  - L'Amerique (JHH# 729 / Enregistre# 1783) (Folder Portfolio 14-1A)
  - L'Asie (JHH# 1347 / Enregistre# 1785) (Folder Portfolio 14-1A)
    19th Century French Stipple engraving
    Artist: Printmaker: Publisher: Jean
  - Afrique (JHH# 1482 / Enregistre# 1786) (Folder Portfolio 14-1A)
    Artist: N. Maurin Printmaker: Villard Publisher: Desmaisons Fils
  - L'Asie (JHH# 1569 / Enregistre# 1788) (Folder Portfolio 14-1A)
    Artist: Sornet Printmaker: Publisher: Marotte arotte
  - L'Afrique (JHH# 1570 / Enregistre# 1789) (Folder Portfolio 14-1A)
  - L'Amerique (JHH# 1571 / Enregistre# 1790) (Folder Portfolio 14-1A)
  - Aviation- New-York-Herald (JHH# 1581 / Enregistre# 1791) (Folder Portfolio 14-1A)